MANOJ AJABRAO RAUT

SUMMARY

Software Team Lead having strong background in .Net and Cloud technologies. I offer excellent supervisory and leadership abilities combined with technical mind. I have 14 years of experience in diverse domains like Shipping, Banking and telecom.

EDUCATION

B.E. IT: 2005 – 2009 from SGB Amravati university

WORK EXPERIENCE

Organization	Role	Duration
Maersk Global Service Centre Ltd, Pune	Team Lead	Jan 2018 - Present
Infosys Ltd	Technology Analyst	Feb 2014- Jan 2018
Tech Mahindra Ltd.	Software Engineer	Oct 2010 – Feb 2014

SKILLS TECHNOLOGIES & FRAMEWORKS:

C#, .Net Core, .Net Framework, Confluent Kafka, EF Core, Microservices, Docker Containers, SQL, UI Automation and RPA (Automation anywhere), SSIS, Angular

CLOUD:

Azure, Confluent Kafka

TOOLS:

Visual Studio, Github, CI/CD using Git Actions, Confluence, Jira, Apigee, Swagger, Postman, xUnit, SVN, SQL Server Management Studio.

EXPERIENCE

Maersk: Team Lead (Jan 2018 - Till date)

COMET (Jan 2021 - Till Date)

Role: Team Lead

Container Operations Management & Event Tracking (COMET) is the intelligent container information system and heartbeat of Maersk. COMET is the foundation for better decision making for all container operations management functions and integrated platforms in Maersk. In COMET, currently we are migrating existing functionalities from a legacy system into a new cloud-based system.

Responsibilities:

- Co-ordinated with product owners to gather requirements and breaking up requirement into different stories.
- Designing and implementing the changes.

- Groom the story and estimate it based on complexity.
- Maintaining the releases in git as well as in JIRA.
- Involved in designing microservices based architecture for all backend services. We are
 using Azure Kubernetes Services (AKS) to deploy all our microservices as docker
 containers.
- Introduced eventing-based design in Comet using Confluent Kafka.

Technologies/Services involved: .Net Core, EF Core, Confluent Kafka, Azure Kubernetes Services, Azure SQL, Azure KeyVault, GitHub actions, Grafana, .Net core API, Angular

Intermodal (Aug 2019 – Dec 2020) **Role:** Senior programmer specialist

Intermodal freight involves the transportation of freight in intermodal container or vehicles, using multiple modes of transportation. This involves the creation of work order required to gate in trucker to terminal.

Responsibilities

- Proactively connect with business users for their requirements and challenges they are facing.
- Prepare business requirement documents, design etc.
- Build the business logic.
- Performing unit testing.
- Prepare test cases and involve in UAT

Technologies involved: .Net UI Automation, SQL, .Net Core., Angular

Book To Load (Feb 2018 – Aug 2019) **Role**: Senior programmer specialist

BTL (Book to Load) is a complete shipping process which involves all operations for vessel loading. This process mainly covers the container stowage planning, capacity planning, preparing and sending different reports to Terminals within specified SLA. There are multiple applications involved in this and the BTL automation uses those to perform operations without any manual intervention.

Technologies involved: .Net UI Automation, SQL, .Net Core.

Infosys Ltd: Technology analyst (Feb 2014 - Jan 2018)

Automation Anywhere (May 2016 – Jan 2018)

Role: Technology analyst

Automation Anywhere is a key application for clients, focusing on automating existing processes within the bank. This application has automated numerous processes, significantly speeding up operations for the client.

WING (Feb 2014 – May 2016) Role: Technology analyst

WING is one of the biggest and most important application for client. This is redesign of legacy application. This application process large number of transactional data, applies some business rules and generate reports which is used by controllers across the bank.

Technologies/Services involved: .Net, MSBI, VBA

Tech Mahindra Ltd (Oct 2010 – Feb 2014) **Number portability** (Apr 2011 – Feb 2014)

Role: Software engineer

The Number Portability application operates on both Windows and web-based platforms, facilitating fixed-line (landline) number portability (NP). It interacts with other licensed operators (OLO) in the European region. NP requests are captured by an upstream application and forwarded to the Number Portability application, which processes, validates, and then sends these requests to the appropriate licensed operator. All data exchanges between the Number Portability application and OLO are conducted via XML. Responsibilities:

- Understand requirement for change in a process of communication to Telecom Italia.
- Thoroughly understand the process flow and identify weaknesses in the current system.
- Design an elegant, user-friendly interface.
- Draft impact analysis documents.
- Develop both Windows and web services.
- Create database objects such as triggers, procedures, and tables.
- Perform unit testing.

Technologies involved: C#.NET, ASP, VBA, Oracle

PEGASO (Nov 2010 – Feb 2011)

Role: Software engineer

Pegaso is web enable application which acts as a gateway of telecom operator in European region like Telecom Italia, Wind etc. and British Telecom. Pegaso deals with requests for Asymmetric digital subscriber line (ADSL), Local Loop Unbundling (ULL) and Carrier preselect (CPS). Orders are captured through CRM easy cell and sent to Hermes. Hermes Process the requests and send it to appropriate component depending upon the service requested. These requests are processed in Pegaso and send these requests to Telecom Italia. Telecom Italia validate the requests and send notification back to Pegaso application, which then updates to the Hermes system. All communication is done through XML.

Technologies involved: ASP, C#.NET, VBA, Oracle.